socialstudies.org 2019-12-01

# NCSS Privacy Policy | National Council for the Social Studies

National Council for the Social Studies respects your privacy. We will make every reasonable effort to ensure that any personal information you provide to us is used only for the purposes stated below. While the policy presented here concentrates on the information that National Council for the Social Studies ("NCSS") and its affiliates and partners collect in connection with the operation of its websites (collectively, the "Site"), it also applies to personal information submitted by other means (mail, fax, phone, sign-up sheets, and so on).All of the information that you provide on the Site is maintained by NCSS or service providers acting on behalf of NCSS. 

You can access some areas of the site without submitting any personally identifiable information. Several areas of the NCSS website require that you send us personal information, including but not limited to:

  * Membership applications 
  * Conference, workshop and webinar registrations 
  * Convention session and webinar applications 
  * Award application and nomination forms
  * Committee, board and volunteer applications
  * NCSS Connected website postings 
  * Rho Kappa application and renewal forms
  * Book and merchandise orders

This information is received offline as well (mail, fax, phone). 

Personal information collected includes name, your school or business name, mailing address, phone, fax, and e-mail address and demographic information. NCSS uses the demographic and professional information collected on membership, convention, and other forms for aggregate analysis, to personalize our member records for better service, and to create targeted mailing lists. Aggregate demographic is may be shared with third-parties.

In addition to the primary purpose stated or implied at the time the information is collected, we may use your postal or email address to send you information about NCSS programs or products, surveys, etc. 

On occasion, the NCSS provides access to its mail and e-mail lists to third parties, who use these lists to inform our members of products and services that may be of interest. Telephone numbers are never provided or rented to third parties. NCSS carefully reviews all requests for mail and e-mail list rentals from third parties to ensure that the products being promoted are relevant to reading professionals. 

Members can at any time request that their names be removed from mail and/or e-mail list rentals by visiting their online account, or on contacting the [NCSS membership department](mailto:membership@ncss.org?subject=mail%20list%20opt%20out). Such requests should include the requestor's name, membership number (if applicable), complete postal address, and e-mail address.

## Credit Card Information

Some areas of the site require that you submit credit card information for payments. Credit card information that you submit through an NCSS site is submitted directly to a secure, third-party [payment processor](http://www.authorize.net/). NCSS does not store credit card numbers on our servers.

## NCSS Members

Because of the special relationship we seek to maintain with our members, NCSS sends them periodic updates and announcements by e-mail. We may also make an occasional phone call (e.g., to clear up a problem or inquire about a lapsed membership). NCSS members have their own online profile page where they can specify their preferred phone number and mailing address.

NCSS provides as a service to its members the ability to search for other members through the member services website. Your contact information will be available to other members through this directory.

NCSS also makes available to members and other parties contact information for members who serve on committees, task forces, are affiliate council leaders or associated group leaders, or are Community chairs or contact persons.

## Conference Attendee Information

On occasion, NCSS rents conference attendee contact information to conference exhibitors who use these lists to inform attendees of special meeting functions, social events associated with the meeting, or other offers and invitations. Registrants request that their names be not be included in such rentals at the time of registration, or at any time by contacting the [NCSS Meetings Department](mailto:conference@ncss.org). Such requests should include the requestor's name, membership number, (if applicable), complete postal address, and e-mail address. 

Conference Attendee information is also encoded on conference badges. This barcode can be shared with conference exhibitors to share contact information. 

## "Anonymous" information collected online

Generally speaking, you can visit the NCSS website without revealing any personal information about yourself. We do keep a record of all server activity, which means that every page, image, or other type of file requested by your browser is written into a log file. Each entry in the log contains, among other things, information about the computer you're using to connect to the Internet (its "IP address") and about your browser (e.g., which version of Firefox you're using). It does not, however, tell us anything about you personally. We use aggregate data from the web logs to determine how the site's resources are being used and to refine its navigational structure. If the need arises, we may use the logs to trace the source of abusive or illicit activity. We do not share our web server logs with any outside party unless required to do so by law or legal process or otherwise requested by any law enforcement officer or agency acting under color of law.

## Cookies

NCSS collects cookies on our Web site to capture information about page visits. This information is anonymous and NCSS uses this information only internally - to deliver the most effective content to our visitors. Information from the cookies is used to gauge page popularity, analyze traffic patterns on our site and guide development of other improvements to our site. 

NCSS does not require that you accept cookies, however, some functionality on our web site, including member-only resources, our product or service check-out process, and other products and services may be disabled if you decline to accept cookies. You can set your browser to notify you when you receive a cookie, giving you the chance to decide whether or not to accept it. 

NCSS uses analytics data and the [DoubleClick][2] cookie to serve ads based on a user's prior visits to our website. Site visitors may opt out of the [DoubleClick][2] cookie by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page][3] or they may opt out of Google Analytics by visiting the [Google Analytics opt- out page][4].

Google has additional information available about their [Remarketing Privacy Guidelines][5], [Policies][6], and [Restrictions][7].

## Material submitted online

Some areas of the NCSS Connected section of the website allow you to submit items for discussion or share information with other members. All submissions become the property of NCSS. For more information, please see the [Code of Conduct](http://connected.socialstudies.org/codeofconduct)

## Links to other websites

The NCSS website contains links to other websites. NCSS is not responsible for the privacy practices or content of those sites. Check the privacy policy of a website before revealing any personal information.

## Exceptions

NCSS may disclose your personally identifiable information if required to do so by law or legal process or otherwise requested by any law enforcement officer or agency acting under color of law. In addition, NCSS reserves the right to disclose your personally identifiable information based on the good faith belief that such action is necessary or appropriate to: (a) protect and defend the rights or property of NCSS, or (b) act in urgent circumstances to protect the safety or security of the public or of users of the NCSS's services and/or the site.

## Privacy policy updates

We have tried to create a privacy policy that is comprehensive, readable, and durable. Despite our best efforts, we may find it necessary to revise it. Any changes will be made without prior notice. The current NCSS privacy policy will continue to be posted at this address ([www.socialstudies.org/privacy](https://www.socialstudies.org/privacy)). If you have questions or comments about our privacy policy, please email [webmaster@ncss.org](mailto:webmaster@ncss.org).

(July 2014)
